FirstLine
SecondLine
With programming it's a...
you can do whatever you want.
プログラミングを使えば、どんなことでも可能だ。
And at some point you, it's...
ある時点で、、
Um, I wouldn't say biblical, but it's like
there's nothing in the beginning
聖書的な事を言おうとしているわけじゃないんだけど、
はじめそこには何も無くて、
Or, or just as you have in history
it's just an empty space
もしくは、歴史に出てくるみたいに言うなら、
そこにはまず何もない空間があって、
and you can start throwing things in there.
そこに、何か物を投げ込む事が出来る
Well, what I want to do when I,
I want to program like I can think.
やりたいことは、思考するようにプログラムをする事だ。
So like ten years ago I painted a lot,
and I want to get the same feeling with code.
十年前に僕は絵をたくさん描いていた。
コードを書く事でそれと同じ感覚を得たいんだ。
Programming is like a superpower.
プログラミングは強力よ。
There's so many things that you want to do
that you could do by hand
すごく沢山のやりたい事を、自分の手で実現できる。
and it would take you a long time but if,
like, programming just increases your capabilities
それには長い時間がかかるかもしれないけど、もしも
プログラミングが人間の能力を単に拡張しているのだとしたら、
you know, almost exponentially.
それはほぼ指数関数的なものなの。
I've always been fascinated by computers.
僕は常にコンピュータに魅了されてきた。
I think Jobs, quite, is particularly interesting.
特にジョブスの言っている事は、非常に興味深い。
You know, saying that computers
are bicycles for the mind.
ご存知のように、彼はコンピュータは知性の自転車だと言ってる。
You know just a human on it's own is just a human.
当たり前だけど、自分の力だけで生きている人間はただの人間だ。
But with the addition of a bicycle
we'll become the most efficient biped out there.
しかし自転車の力を借りれば、僕らは世界で
最も効率のいい二足歩行動物になる。
And the computer I think holds
the same thing in terms of
コンピュータは僕らの創造性の可能性に関して、
同じポジションにあると思う。
the possibilities of what we can do with our creativity.
（18に入れました）
And when you have that computer to support you
you can create incredible things.
コンピュータの助けを借りれば、
驚くような物を作り出す事が出来る。
I addicted myself (to coding).
僕は中毒だ。
And, I'm highly addicted to programming.
You can't stop me, sometimes I forget to eat.
重度のプログラミング中毒だ。僕を止める事はできない。
まれに食べる事も忘れる。
Sometimes I forget to sleep.
たまには寝る事もね。
And...
そして
I don't know, can you turn a pickle back into a cucumber?
よく分からないな。ピクルスをキュウリに戻す事は出来る？
Probably not. So I'm here for life.
You've got me, it's terminal.
多分無理だね。僕は人生でその辺にいる。
分かるかな。それは終点なんだ。
You are sculpting possibility space.
あなたは可能性の空間を彫刻している。
Which sounds big, but in a way that's what it is.
大きく聞こえるかもしれないけど、でもある種、そういう事だ。
You're adding with those little lego bricks
of code and language that you have.
貴方は自分の小さなコードと言語のレゴブロックを積み上げている。
Put them together and you add more possibilities.
足し合わせて、さらに多くの可能性を足していく。
And with every new brick, basically
your possibilities increase, uh, many times.
そして、新しいブロックを追加するたびに
基本的には貴方の可能性は増していく。何度も。
And that's, in a way this adding and taking away,
that's kind of the design process now.
それでそれは足したり引いたりする作業をしていくわけだけど、
それはある種のデザインプロセスになっている。
It's… I still feel in control.
それは、まだ自分のコントロール下にあると感じている。
Uh, but I like to be surprised.
I think that's the beauty of it.
だけど、僕は驚かされたい。それがその美しさだと思うからだ。
Um, the thing when a system goes beyond
what you naturally understand it to do.
システムが元々把握していたよりも、ずっとうまく動くことがあって、
And sometimes you have something that surprises you.
時々、驚かせてくれるような物が出来る事がある。
And I always look for that, that one moment, basically.
僕は基本的に、常にそういうもの、そういう瞬間を探している。
In my practice as an artist,
I've always been interested about the universe
僕がアーティストとして実践してきた中で、
常に興味を引かれているのは宇宙に関する事だ。
and the scale of the universe that's around us.
Especially in comparison to us.
我々を取り囲む宇宙の大きさ、特に我々自身と比較したときのね。
And, uh, and I think kind of the commercial work that I do
僕がやっているコマーシャルの仕事などを考えると、
it's really about trying to take people into the moment.
僕はまさにそういう瞬間を作る事にトライしている。
I'm really trying to get people into that kind of feeling
過去や未来の事を考えない場所にいるような、
where you're not thinking about your past, or your future.
そういう感覚を抱かせるように。
That you're really in the now.
本当に今に存在しているという感覚をね。
[clears his throat]
I dream in code.
僕はコードを書いている夢を見る。
One time I woke up and I said:
一度、起きて言った事がある。
Rebecca! What time is it?
And then I said:
レベッカ！今の時間は？それからこういったんだ。
I think it's January 11111111111!
Like that.
今日は一月の11111111111日だ！
こんな感じで。
In 1999, I was making out with my girlfriend
Anne Marie
1999年、僕はガールフレンドのアンマリーといちゃいちゃしていて、
and I fell asleep because I was very tired.
僕はあまりにも疲れていたので眠ってしまった。
And I could see the function with a block of code
with if then statements and for loops
そしたらif-then文やらループ構造なんかを含んだ、
ある機能をもつコードのブロックが浮かんできて、
describing the, um... the kiss.
それはキスについて書かれたコードだった。
I think, coding and technology in general
informatic technology is the thing
コーディングとテクノロジー、一般的に言って
情報テクノロジーは、
that defines our time right now
and as an artist, I feel like
私たちの時間を今に規定する。
アーティストとして私が感じている事は、
my job is to explore this stuff that defines our time right now.
私の仕事は、時間を今に規定するような物を掘り下げていく事だという事。
Not the stuff that defined our time 100 years ago.
時間を100年前に規定するようなものじゃなくてね。
So, I just got into it naturally.
だから私は自然とそれにのめりこんでしまったの。
You know we have people who write demos in 256 bytes.
ご存知のように、256バイトでデモを作る人がいる。
These are 256 numbers strung together
to create an image or an animation
256個の数字が並んでいるだけで、
それでなんらかのイメージかアニメーションを作る。
and everyone goes WOW, how did they do that?
それでみんなワオ！となって、どうやって作ったんだ？？となる。
And this is incredible, because the way actually
you can only achieve this by
信じられない事だけど、これを実現するためには、
knowing every single bit about the technology underneath.
裏側にある各ビット（0と1）全ての意味を知っている必要がある。
Knowing what command to use in which position
so you can actually reuse the code as data
どの場所でどのコマンドが使用されているか、を知っている事で、
実際にコードをデータとして再利用する事が出来る。
to create something else.
And it's incredibly cryptic
（コードとしてではなくて）何かほかの物を作るためにね。
信じられないほど暗号めいているけど、
but it shows incredible mental strength
and intelligence
本当にそんな事を実現するための、信じがたい精神力の強さと、
知性を見せている。
to actually achieve something  like that.
(66に入れた)
Like it's a way to interface with these things
that's on a very basic level of the way that we
それはこれらの事へのインターフェースの一つだと思う。
それは凄く基本的なレベルの、私たちが経験をプロセスする手段なの。
you know, process our experience.
And I think that's like a big problem with software.
（一行目は68へ）
そして、私はそれがソフトウェアに関しての大きな問題だと考えていて、
It's so abstracted on so many levels.
それは非常に多くの段階で抽象的になっている。
You know data on it's own is just noise.
If no one processes that data it's meaningless.
データはそれ自体だけではただのノイズだ。
データはプロセスを加えなければ、意味を持たない。
It's really just dust, you know?
ただのゴミなんだ。知ってますよね？
And that's what I really find interesting about the demo scene
そして、さっきのデモの話において、その事が本当に面白いと思っている。
because it's actually, people are really focused
なぜなら、実際に、人々がフォーカスしているのが
on producing such compressed
versions of information.
そのような、圧縮された情報を創り出す事だからだ。
Not data. Code is information.
データではない。コードは情報なんだ。
It's not random noise.
無作為な乱数ではない。
That information can actually create a physical
emotional feedback in the viewer.
それらの情報が物理的な、感情のフィードバックを見ている人に喚起する。
And I find this really incredible.
And the code is so microscopic
僕はこれが本当に信じがたい事だと思った。
そしてコードは本当に微視的に書かれている。
it can be easily shared.
そして簡単にシェアする事が出来る。
And it was like, um, I liked it visually.
Just because of the shapes you got.
それはなんというか、僕は視覚的に好きなんだ。
単に得られる形状がね。
But I also liked it in a sense of, um
...experimenting.
でも同時に、体験、、という意味でも好きなんだ。
So it was like, I couldn't do this with actual water in a tank.
それは例えば、僕はこれを実際のタンクに入った水では出来ないけど、
But here I can do it on a smaller scale.
だけど、小さめなスケールで同じ事をすることができる。
And, just imagine what it might look like.
それがどんな事になるのか、想像してみて欲しい。
There's a guy I know who made this project
僕の知っている人でこのプロジェクトを作った人がいて、
it was just these strings in a box, and it was called Wiremap.
箱の中にこういう弦が入ってるだけなんだけど、それはワイアーマップという作品だった。
And you were able to present like, 3D objects inside it
この凄く安い素材だけを使って、3Dの物体が中に入っているかのように、
like dynamically, using these really cheap materials.
ダイナミックに見せる事が出来る。
It was really inspiring, it was like
それは本当に想像をかきたてられるような作品で、それは、
a video projector, which you can get ahold of
almost anywhere now, and some strings in a box.
ビデオプロジェクター、これは今はほとんどどこででも手に入るし、
それと、箱に入った何本かの弦で出来ている。
But all the string's like perfectly laid out,
so each one of them catches
けれど全ての弦が完璧に並べられていて、それぞれが、
a different column of pixels from the projector.
プロジェクタから投影される、違った列のピクセルに対応してマッピングされている。
So I started recreating this project and I worked
a lot in like how to make it more advanced
それで僕はそのプロジェクトを再制作し始めた。たくさんの時間を
どうやったらもっと高度な事が出来るかに費やした。
in terms of the algorithms behind it.
裏側にあるアルゴリズムをいかに良くできるかという意味でね。
So there's now an interest in really thinking about interface.?
今はインターフェースに関して真剣に考える事に関心が集まってる。
So on one hand that's quite interesting
それはとても興味深いのだけど、でもその一方で、
And then, but I think what's more exciting is that
uh, is the people hacking them.
もっと興味深いと思えるのは、人々がそれらをハッキングしているという事。
And that those communities are going to
discover actually the more interesting things.
そして、そのコミュニティは実際にさらに多くの面白い事を発見しようとしている。
I think you get to a point in large visualizations where
大規模なビジュアリゼーションでは、それは実フラットなイメージとしてみるには
it's just actually too much data to look at as a flat image
実際にはデータ量が多すぎるという事が分かってくれたと思う。
（100と混ぜた）
and you have to do some sort of zooming or
you know, flying through navigation to get
それで、ナビゲーションを通じて、ある種のズームとかデータ間を
飛び回るような移動をしなくてはならないの。
I don't know, to focus on some small part of it
because it's, there's so many examples of this like
分からないわ。例えば巨大なつながりをもつ、それ自体はある時点では
意味をなしていなかったりするような毛玉があって、そんな多くの例があるのだけど、
huge hairball of connections
and like it means nothing, at some point.
その中のある小さなエリアにフォーカスするためにね。
And he is basically explaining
how the database works
それで彼は基本的にデータベースが基本的にどのように動くかについて説明しているんだ。
and he says there's one point here,
そこで彼は言う。ここに一つのポイントがあって、
and then you go around and then there is another
audio sample there, and another one there
それでその周りをいけば、ほかのオーディオサンプルが、
さらにまたほかのものも見つかる。
and because this is closer this is the
one which is matched.
それで、これがほかの物よりもそのポイントに近かったという理由で
この一つがマッチする。
[laughs]
And he explains everything like that.
そして彼は全てがこのような感じで動いていると説明する。
I think like for a little while people will still be
doing this thing with augmented reality
ここほんのしばらくの間、人々はまだこれをオーギュメンテッドリアリティ (AR)でやっている。
--in the near future, but in the real future, it's not gonna
where they'd get like an iPad out and
they'd put it in front of something.
iPadを使って、何かの前に置いてみたりね。
but that's just ridiculous.
It's never going to be like that eventually.
でもそれは馬鹿げていて、それは絶対最終的には残らない。
It's all going to be about like,
you go around the world
それらは総じてなんというか、世界を行き来してたら、
and things happen that
couldn't have happened before.
以前は起こりえなかった事が起こる。
You can see something.
I mean you might be looking
何かが目に見えるんだ。君はこっちを見てるかもしれない、
over here and you might,
this thing might pop up that says
そしたらそこに何かが飛び出してくるかもしれなくて、それで
here's a read-out from this thing.
これがそれについての情報ですよ、と教えてくれるかもしれない。
And it'd be perfectly rectified
to the way you're looking at it
さらにそれは普段人の視覚に違和感を感じさせないように
完全に補正されているかもしれない。
but somebody over there won't
be able to see it at all.
だけどほかの人たちには、それは全く見えない。
But you won't be wearing anything. You'll just be,
けれどなんの装置も身につける必要は無くて、ただそこにいると、
your environment is having this light cast onto it
君を取り囲む環境に、そういった光が投影されるんだ。
because it's being scanned
and projected onto. And, uh
なぜなら、環境はスキャンされていて、その上に投影されているからだ。
I think that's like, that's gonna be really interesting in the future.
僕はこんな事が未来において、面白い事になると思う。
It's very difficult to take your mind
out of what you are living
意識を普段の生活から切り離すのはとても難しいわ。
where everything is already so fast
普段の生活では全てが常にとても早いし、
and there's always a new app and and a new,
a new innovation and something you want to try
そして常に新しいアプリケーションや、新しいイノベーション、
それからトライしたい事がいくつもある。
because you just read about it so
also the information like circulates so fast that
ちょうどそういう記事を読んでしまったし、
情報は早い速度で循環するから。
yeah, it's um... it's really difficult
to project yourself in the future
未来に自身を投影するのはとても難しいわ。
because you feel almost like you are already
living in some kind of future.
なぜなら、既に貴方はある種の未来を生きていると感じているから。
Even if you fantasize about having
a more powerful laptop.
たとえもっと高性能なラップトップコンピュータを持つ事を夢に描いていたとしても。
Interviewer: "Is there an experience,
a digital experience, that you desire to have?"
インタービュアー：「体験したいデジタル体験はありますか？」
Oh yes, tele-transportation. Yeah. That's a, that's
there are many things,
あるわ、瞬間移動。ほかにもたくさんあるわ。
Yeah, there, there are many things, OK.
Some I shouldn't talk about.
たくさんあるわ。OK。話すべきじゃないのもいくつかあるけど。
But yeah, tele-transportation, it's because,
you know there was a time when they would say
瞬間移動はなぜかというと、かつて人々が、
ビデオカンファレンスが実現すれば、
well with video conferences you won't need
to meet, but they don't work so well.
人に会う必要はなくなる、と言っていた時代があった
けれど、結局そうはなっていない。
You still need to be with the people, to really
discuss and work on projects.
真剣に話し合って、プロジェクトを進めていくためには、
未だに人と会う必要がある。
You can do part of it by video conferences,
部分的にはビデオカンファレンスでも可能だけど、
but it has its limits, so it means I have to travel.
そこには限界がある。それで、移動をしなければならないと。
I am sick of traveling. I waste so much time
私は旅行にうんざりしていて。時間を浪費しすぎるわ。
in the airport, and waiting for trains,
and I cannot work, so, I wish tele-transportation
空港で、電車の待ち時間で、しかも仕事できない。だから瞬間移動が良いわ。
Is it, is it possible? Is it going to be possible?
I really want that.
それって可能なのかしら？可能になるのかしら？本当に欲しい。
You could start off with the point cloud of this.
And then, I don't know, at some point when I say
君はこのポイントクラウドからスタートできた。
それで、分からないけど、あるとき僕と
talking about water or physical systems
all the points could just flush, or
水や、物理システムの事を話しているときに、
そのポイントクラウド全てが流れ出して
or turn into water,
もしくは、水になって
or something like that. Just to
illustrate the thing you've been talking about.
とかそういう感じで。それまで話していた事を説明するためにね。
The footage is frameless, so because this
footage is rendered in a 3D environment
その映像にはフレームがなくて、3Dの空間内にレンダリングされている。
and you have to look at it from some perspective
you can browse anywhere in it
だからもしその映像をある画角から見なくてはならなくても、その3D空間内を自由にブラウズできる。
you can see just edges of it,
or potentially multiple people
角の部分だけを見る事も出来るし、もしくは複数の人を見る事も可能だ。
you know like floating heads or whatever,
can be in the same space
浮遊している頭とか、なんでもいい、同じ空間に存在する事が出来る。
or having a conversation that never happened.
もしくは起こりえなかった状況で会話をしているとか、
Or objects can come in,
or parts of things can be taken out
もしくは複数の物体が入って来れて、または物体の一部を取り出す事が出来たり。
um, that can illustrate what they're talking about.
Or even simpler things like that, like
それで彼らが話している事を説明できる。
もしくはもっとシンプルな事でもいい、例えば、
the faces can fragment,
or um, the colors can change.
顔が砕けてしまうような事が可能だったりとか、色を変える事が出来たりとか。
Or the camera angle can change even though
this camera's been completely static.
または現実のカメラのポジションが完全に固定だったとしても
カメラアングルを変える事ができたりとか。
There's just a lot of room to play.
It's an experimentation.
そこにはいくらでも遊べる余地が残っている。それは実験だ。
You don't know what will work. There's no
cinematic language that has evolved yet
どんな風になるか分からないけど、まだそこには既存の映像用語は何もないんだ。
so we're sort of at a point to define that.
だから、僕たちは今その用語を決定する段階にいる。
[quiet overlapping voices]
It's the thing that comes after a video camera.
It's the thing that comes after a camcorder.
これはビデオカメラの次にくる物だね。
これはカムコーダーの次にくる物だ。
It's a Kinect with a digital camera on it,
I guess there's a sound microphone.
これはデジタルカメラをキネクトの上に乗せた物で、
さらにマイクがある思う。
And there's this amazing blinding light.
そしてこのすばらしい不可視の光がある。
I mean we definitely are stuck in that paradigm.
私たちは確実にそのパラダイムで行き詰まっている。
We're stuck in the mirror world you know?
鏡の世界で立ち往生してしまっているの。
Like, I look at this, and I do this, and stare
at myself in the screen that's like in here
例えば私がこれを見る。それでこれをする。
それでスクリーンの中の私自身をそこにいるかのように見る。
you know, so that's an issue.
それが問題。
AndÔøΩ I don't know how you could fix that.
This is still a camera
貴方がどうやって解決したのか私には分からないんだけど。
これはいずれにしてもカメラでしょ。
it still has all of the like, dynamics and
kind of set up that a camera makes, so
これには依然としてカメラの作り出すダイナミクスや
カメラのセットアップがあって、
and like the politics of
the camera world, you know
それはカメラの世界の政治のようなもので、
I wouldn't want to have that inhibition there.
I wouldn't want to have it sitting there
私はそういった制限はいらないし、
カメラ自体がここにある事も望まないわ。
and reminding me to like, look at the image
the way that the camera looked at it.
私は、カメラが私を見ていたように、
私がイメージを見ているという事を思い出す。
I mean, if that's 3D, then let's turn it inside out.
Let's look at it from behind.
何を言っているかというと、この3Dのイメージだとしたら、
裏返してみたり、後ろから見てみようという事になるでしょ。
Let's break down the image that you get.
撮影したイメージをばらばらに分解してみましょうよ。
For me, I perceive a continuum between
abstraction and figuration.
私は抽象化された物と実際の形状の間の連続体を受容している。
I see a place all along there where there's a lot
of really interesting places to go
私は、その連続体を見ている。そこには本当に興味深い所が多い。
that communicate with us
in so many interesting ways.
それは我々と非常に多くの興味深い方法でコミュニケーションしている。
And seeing a host of new aesthetic approaches
coming into wider use
新しい美学的アプローチの扱いの手法がより広く使用されるようになるのを見ていると、
And seeing the very sort of non-photorealistic
aspects of that film
そしてその映像の非写実的な側面みたいなものを見ていると、
that sort of made me excited for what
we can accomplish if we just sort of
なんというか、あまり恐れずに現実を複製し、どうやったらこのような、
今までになかったようなイメージを作り出せるかを考えて
(179-181は混ざってる)
don't worry so much about duplicating reality
and figure out how to create kinds of images
実現していったときに、僕たちが何を実現できるのかといった事について
that have never been seen before.
エキサイティングな気持ちにさせられる。
Further into the future I think we could
probably see autonomous cameras
さらに未来になると、自律的に動作するカメラが出来ると思う。
Cameras that can hover, or move on their own.
自分で浮かび上がって、自分自身で動くカメラがね。
And paint areas, creating you know
large sets of data
それでカメラは領域を描いていって、膨大な量のデータを創り出す。
that you choose camera angles
out of after the fact.
それでそこから事後的に、カメラアングルを決めるんだ。
And, uh, do my own performance,
and then blend that
それから、僕自身のパフォーマンスをする。それからそれと、
with the existing point cloud
that you give me
君のくれるポイントクラウドとブレンドする。
so that I'm doing an additional
layer of extemporaneous performance
それで、僕はレイヤーを足して、そこでポイントクラウドを
which moves and changes.
動かし変化させるような即興パフォーマンスをする。
One me this month, one me next month.
And maybe another me the month after.
この月の一つの自分、翌月の一つの自分、
さらにひと月後にはさらにほかの自分。
And have a different algorithmic
treatment per word.
単語ごとに違ったアルゴリズムで処理をするんだ。
But I just want to try and explore
every path that it opens
だけど、それがもたらす全ての可能性を試してみたいだけなのよ。
And see what connections we can make
and how we can build on that.
それで私たちがどんなつながりを作れるか、またその上でどうやって物が作れるかを知りたいの。
I hope there are no limitations and
I don't think there will be.
そこに制限がなければ良いと思うし、僕はないと思う。
The only limitation is time,
and we probably won't live to
唯一の制限は時間だ。そして多分、今、その僕たちが制限だと考えているような事を
see things we would think
is a limitation right now.
感じるまで生きる事は無いと思う。
But I do think it gets more and more complex
けれど、やはり僕はどんどん複雑になっていくと思う。
And it's, I mean, it's such a young medium
as well. And it's evolving so fast
それは、なんというか、そんなまだ若いメディアも同じ事で、
それは凄く早い速度で進化していく。
All this computation and power, I mean we...
全てのこの計算力は
if you look at where we are with our tools
that we have available , um
もし僕らと、今手に入る僕らのツール、その状況を見てみれば、
we've got the basic needs covered.
The basic input, output, interaction, rendering
基本的なニーズはカバーされている。
基本的なインプット、アウトプット、インタラクション、レンダリング、
That's, that's done. And people
don't predict big advances there.
それらは既にできている。
人々はもうその辺りの事に大きな進歩を予測していない。
There's the limit of our physical senses
そこには我々の物理的な感覚の限界がある。
is kind of the limit of where real and virtual
kind of overlaps and meets.
それはリアルとバーチャル、それと、それらが重なりあう領域、境界での限界だ。
That's visible.
それは目に見えている。
I mean, Tim Sweeney from Epic Games says that
in 2020, at that point in time we'll have
エピックゲームズのティムスウィーニーが言っている。
2020年の時点で、
graphics cards producing,
and 3D game engines producing
グラフィックカードは、そして3Dゲームエンジンは
visuals that can fool our eyes believably enough
我々の目を十分に信じさせて騙すだけのビジュアルを作れるだろうと。
and, so all this extra computation power
from then on hopefully will be spent on
そしてそれ以外の残り全ての計算力は願わくば
developing deeper knowledge systems
that can do something like
意識をモデリングしたり、さらに複雑な、深いインタラクションを
modeling consciousness, or create more
complex, deeper interactions.
もたらすような、より深いナレッジシステムを創り出す事に使われるだろう。
And I think that's where
I'd love cinema to see to go to
そして僕が見たい映画はそれなんだ。
where we can play with these virtual actors
and we can interact with them
そこではバーチャルな役者達と遊ぶ事が出来て、彼らと交流し合う事が出来る。
on a believable, deeper, human level.
信じる事が出来て、より深く、人間レベルで。
Hopefully it'll all resolve into
one big global conversation.
願わくばその全ては一つの大きくてグローバルな会話に集約されれば良いと思う。
And there you can definitely
see the cumulative effects
そして無数の神経で構築されたインターネットの、もしくはネットワークの、
というべきかもしれないが、
of you know, an internet which is, or a network
rather, of millions of neurons.
そこで確実に累積的な効果を見る事が出来る。
Kevin Kelly's observations of the complexity of
the entire sphere of connected, um, computers
ケヴィンケリーのコンピュータ接続による地球全体の複雑さに関する観察によると、
is approximately right now on the order of
the same size as a single human brain.
その複雑さは現時点でおおよそ、一人の人間の能と同サイズのオーダーだ。
And it is going to become
very interesting when that
そしてこの複雑さが何億倍にもなったとき、
becomes a hundred million
times more complicated.
凄く面白い事になる。
Um, and that will be like
the greatest network ever built
それは史上、最も偉大なネットワークになる。
and certainly we'll be able to do
some very interesting things
そして確実に、いくつかのとても興味深い事が可能になる。
Um, I think of it as kind of the world
becoming one mind.
なんというか、世界が一つの精神にまとまるというか。
I think it's going to be more like that,
than sort of the computers taking over
私はスカイネットの様にコンピュータが世界を乗っ取るというよりは、もっと
それに近いものになると考えている。
and, you know, Skynet.
（225に入れた）
Um, but maybe I'm an optimist.
しかし、私はある種、楽観的なのかもしれない。
Of sorts.
(227に入れた)
You always feel this layer of artificiality
いつもこの類いの人工的な感じがあるでしょ。
which I'm, I'm...
それは、、
I never managed to truly engage and feel comfortable there, so
私は今まで一度も、本当にそれらに参加して、居心地が良いと感じた事が無いの。
um, so yeah, a virtual version world would
be good, but ones I've tested so far have not
仮想世界は良いかもしれない、けれども今までに試した物はそうでもなかった。
I don't think they can replace physicality.
私はそれらが物理世界を置き換える事になるとは考えていないの。
Doesn't mean that physicality cannot be replaced, but
でもそれは物理世界を置き換えられない、と言っている訳ではないのだけど、
what I've experienced so far
I was not very impressed.
私は今まで体験してきたものに、そこまでの感銘をうけなかったのよ。
What if you could capture the thinking of a person?
人間の思考をキャプチャできるとしたらどうする？
At one point, and then compare
it to another point
ある時点と、それをほかの時点とを比較すると、
and like a really beautiful
multi-complex fractal, in a way.
そしてそれはまるで、ある種、本当に美しい、複数の複雑さを備えたフラクタルのようだ。
And ideally I'd like to kind of put two
next to each other
理想的には、その二つを隣り合わせにおいて、
and compare them or talk to them.
それらを比較する、もしくはそれらに話しかける。
Explore them.
それらを探索する。
And, maybe that goes a bit far.
もしかしたらちょっと行き過ぎかもしれないけど。
In theory you could build the whole universe
inside a computer.
理論的には全宇宙をコンピュータの中に構築できる。
You just don't have enough power and then,
ただ、そうするためには計算力が十分でない、というだけの事だ。
you'll never get there and it would be boring
to build the same thing all over again.
そこには決して行き着けないし、同じ物を再度構築するのは退屈な事かもしれない。
But in theory, you could, and
だけど、理論的には、できる。そして、
that's something I find kind of stunning.
僕はそれは驚くほど魅力的な何かだと思う。